Muhammad Burhan Ahmad

Dubai, UAE

E: muhdburh@gmail.com M: +971521566568

www.linkedin.com/in/burhan066 https://burhanahmad02.github.io/

PROFILE

As a passionate game developer with over two years of experience, I have developed and deployed more than 10 games. I have worked with teams of up to 15 people, managing all aspects of the game development process, from concept to launch. With a strong background in programming, design, and project management, I am committed to creating engaging and immersive game experiences that captivate players. I am eager to continue advancing my knowledge of AI algorithms and their application in game development, with a goal of achieving even greater success in the gaming industry.

EDUCATION

Comsats University Islamabad, Pakistan

BSc Computer Science

2017-2021

TECH SKILLS & PROJECTS

Skills: Unity 3D, C#, Trello, Slack, Source Control, Doxygen

Artificial Intelligence: Computer Vision, Image Processing, Pattern recognition, Machine learning, Image Labelling, Testing, Creating Datasets

Soft-Skills: Leadership, Team-management, Collaborative, Cooperative, Analytical thinking, Team Player

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Game Ever Studio Pvt. Ltd Dubai, UAE Unity Game Developer

April 2022 - Present

Five Ocean 2D

- Implemented mechanics and physics-based Submarine, resulting in a more realistic and engaging gameplay experience
- Designed engaging gameplay with AI detecting hidden enemies and AI spawning, showcasing expertise in game design and programming
- Coded a Radar System which was responsible for detecting enemies with each clockwise rotation of its sweep, resulting in a 30% increase in player engagement

FPS Game

- Crafted seamless gameplay with unique First-Person characters, reactive Enemy AI system, and engaging controls. Translated complex game concepts into an immersive experience
- Overall UI implementation and UI animation

• FPS Sci-fi Game

- Blended technical and artistic skills to design immersive VFX, sound, and shader effects for environments and weapons
- Crafted dynamic, captivating death animations for the player using Cine-machine virtual camera, showcasing a deep understanding of both animation and programming
- Compressed sound and sprite sizes to achieve blazing-fast player experience, optimized with 30mb build size reduction
- Introduced scalable Achievement system with scriptable objects, elevating player experience. Demonstrated exceptional technical and creative skills

Sniper 3D FPS Game

- Devised and developed an Upgrade system for the attachments of the sniper rifles
- Target shooting level, where player can practice their aim and accuracy

Viral Mobi Tech Pvt. Ltd Islamabad, Pakistan Game Developer Jan 2022 – April 2022

- Draw Bridge 2D
 - Established mechanics and physics-based vehicle
 - Utilized line renderer to draw a path with colliders and physics

Spartans Global Pvt. Ltd Islamabad, Pakistan Game Dev Trainee Dec 2020 – Dec 2021

- Santa Pin-pull 2D SGPL Games
 - Leveraged Addressable for optimization of memory for 120 levels
 - Diversified the purchasable and rewarded gifts in the Shop by implementing JSON
- Rush To Crush SGPL Games Unity Game Developer
 - Enacted a bike based on mechanics, physics, and 2D ragdoll physics
 - Setup architecture to shift to scriptable objects
 - Introduced a shared biker rig, for custom animation
- Fashion Makeover SGPL Games Unity Game Developer
 - Designed and implemented architecture using scriptable objects
 - Optimized addressable implementation for scalable item database
 - Collaborated and guided Art and Design teams to ensure the best visuals and performance. Moreover, coordinated all core game mechanics

Potato Knights Pvt. Ltd Islamabad, Pakistan Intern (Game Dev) Jan 2020 – April 2020 EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES & AWARDS

Awards:

- Fast University (Nuces):
 - Nascon-18 participated in Dota2, Nascon-18 participated in FIFA, Nascon-17 participated in Tekken-7 Fast University
- University of Engineering and Technology:
 - Tech-salvo 18 winner for Dota2 UET
- Comecs-18 runner up for Call of duty 4 Comsats University Islamabad

Community meetups:

- Attended a One-day workshop on soft skills and Personality Development in Comsats University Islamabad
- Enhanced professional networking skills with a LinkedIn workshop and programming skills with a C# workshop at Comsats University Islamabad, demonstrating a commitment to ongoing learning